（倫也）しゃっ　ラストスパート！
All right,
one final spurt!
（倫也）《ある春の日…》
One spring day...
I came face to face with my destiny.
《俺は　運命と出合った》
houkago futari de sugoshita kyoushitsu
Whenever we're together in the classroom after school
tsukue no ue muchuu de hazumu kimi no koe
You at your desk, just talking and talking on and on
donkan na kimi no sono taido ga
You're so dense, and it really shows
itsumo watashi wo ijiwaru ni saseru no
And that's why I always have to pick on you
hitoribocchi da to omou toki mo aru
Sometimes I feel like I'm alone
namida tomerarenai hi mo aru
Some days I can't stop myself from crying
hontou no watashi wo mitsumete hoshii no
I want you to look and see the real me
kitto tsutawaru to shinjiteiru yo
I'll keep believing that one day you will
kimi wa itsudatte itsudatte kawaranai kara
But you just never, ever, never, ever change, and so
watashi ga nankai mo nankai mo signal okutteageru
I keep sending and sending and sending and sending the same signal
yume mita ano oka mezashite
Dreaming of the day I'll make it over that hill
kujikesou na toki mo ganbaresou da yo
Even when I feel like giving up, I can keep going on
kimi ga iru kara
Because you're there for me
An Error-ridden Prologue
Whoops.
Planned BD marathons
（倫也）いってきま～す。
See you later!
Amber Concerto
おはよう　おじさん。
Good morning, mister!
あれ　倫也君。
今度は新聞配達かい？→
Oh, Tomoya-kun.
You're delivering papers now?
What happened to your other job?
前　やってたバイトは
どうしたの？
I still work at the video store and the restaurant.
レンタルショップも　ファミレスも続けてるよ。
I've just taken on a morning job as well now.
朝のバイトを　増やしただけ。
You sure are a hard worker.
ホント　働き者だねえ。
Isn't it hard to balance school with all those jobs?
勉強と両立で
大変なんじゃないかい？
大丈夫。　だって　俺
でっかい目標ができたんだ。
I'll manage!
After all, I've given myself a goal to pursue now.
だから　今は　立ち止まってる
暇なんか　ないんだよ！
So I've got no time to hang around and dawdle!
じゃあね！
See you!
What anime's that boy hooked on this time?
今度は　何のアニメに
ハマったのかねえ。
（生徒たち）おはよう。
Morning!
Toyogasaki Private Academy
Aki Tomoya
≪（石巻）おはよう　澤村さん。
（英梨々）あっ。
Aki Tomoya
Good morning, Sawamura-san.
（里見）おはよう。
（英梨々）あっ　ああ。
Good morning.
Oh, how are you today, Ishimaki-san?
（英梨々）ごきげんよう
石巻さん。→
それに　里見さんも。
And you too, Satomi-san?
Oh, Sawamura-san!
≪（生徒）あっ　澤村さん
≪（生徒）おはよう。
Good morning!
Sawamura-san, good morning!
（生徒）澤村さん　おはよう。
（生徒）澤村さん　元気してた～？
Sawamura-san, how have you been?
（石巻）ねえ　ほら　見て。
私たち　同じ　Ｇ組だよ。
It's been too long, Sawamura-san!
Hey, look at that.
We're all in Class G!
Ishimaki Kiyo
O-Oh, we are too.
（英梨々）そっ　そうね。
Ishimaki Kiyo
Satomi Azusa
Sawamura Spencer Eriri
これから　１年間　よろしくね。
Let's have a good year together, then.
（里見）澤村さん？
（英梨々）えっ？
Sawamura-san?
Huh? Oh, it's nothing.
Hey, Tomoya!
（喜彦）よっ　倫也。
喜彦か。
Yoshihiko, is it?
Looks like we're in the same class again this year!
ことしも　同じクラスだな。
I'm a tad busy at the moment.
Please don't bother me.
今　忙しいんだ。
邪魔しないでくれ。
何だよ。　冬アニメの総評か？
Oh, please. With what?
You doing a winter anime roundup?
それとも　３月売りラノベの
レビューか？
Or are you reviewing March's light novels?
I finished all of that ages ago.
そんなの　とっくに終わってる。
I get anime reviews out of the way
within 24 hours of the finale's airing,
アニメなら
最終回放映後　２４時間以内。
light novels within three days of publishing,
ラノベなら　発売３日以内。
ゲームなら　１週間以内。
and games within a week of release.
ちゃんと
ネタバレありなしを分けて→
It's my mission to post useful, spoiler-sorted news for anyone to see and enjoy.
誰が見ても　楽しく役に立つ情報を発信するのが　俺の使命だ。
大手ブロガーは
言うことが違うね。
All you big shot bloggers sure talk differently.
What are you working on now, then?
で　結局　何やってんだよ？
フッ　これはな…。
What you see here is a mission
of the utmost importance.
あっ。
とても重要な　ミッションなんだ。
俺の　新たなオタク人生の
始まりに　ふさわしい→
It is an epic project worth putting
the beginning of my new otaku life into.
超特大プロジェクト…。
おい！　あれ見ろよ　倫也。
Hey, check it out, Tomoya!
What kind of friend asks a question and then ignores the answer?!
質問しておいて　こっちが答えたらいきなりスルーってのは→
友達として　どうなんだよ！
（喜彦）ほら　澤村さんだよ。
Look, it's Sawamura-san!
Sawamura Spencer Eriri.
（喜彦）澤村・スペンサー・英梨々。→
父親が　イギリス外交官の
ハーフお嬢さま。→
Half-Japanese, wealthy,
and daughter of an English diplomat.
Plus, she's the art club's super ace, being accepted into the municipal art exhibition right after enrolling here!
しかも　入学して　すぐに
市の展覧会で入選した→
美術部のスーパーエース。
いまさら　何　興奮してんだよ。
Why are you getting so excited about her now?
（喜彦）いや～　２年になって→
Man, she sure has become a lot cuter
now that she's a second-year.
ますます　かわいさに
磨きが　かかったよなあ　彼女。
まだ　３次元に　未練があるのかよ。
You still haven't let go of 3D girls?
Even after my efforts through all of
first year to get you to fixate on 2D girls.
俺が　１年かけて
２次元に　はめてやったってのに。
お前ってやつは。
What are you saying, you idiot?
バーカ　何言ってんだよ。
だからこそだろ。→
That's exactly it!
She's a fair skinned half-Japanese!
色白！　ハーフ！　金髪！
ツインテール！→
She's sporting blonde hair in twintails!
しかも　ニーソ！
And she's wearing thigh-highs!
２次元的記号だらけの
萌えヒロインじゃないか。
She's a moe heroine with ticks
in every box on the 2D checklist!
バカは　お前だ。
You're the idiot.
３次元ってのはな
もっと　めんどくさいんだよ。
3D girls are way too much trouble.
Concept:
A story of encounter, feelings, and flirtatious love
Prologue
One spring day, I came face to face with my destiny...
Content
The protagonist meets a mysterious, beautiful girl.
The two flirt a little and then share a joyous kiss...
Concept:
A story of encounter, feelings, and flirtatious love
Prologue
One spring day, I came face to face with my destiny...
Content
The protagonist meets a mysterious, beautiful girl.
The two flirt a little and then share a joyous kiss...
おい　倫也。
始業式　出ないのかよ。
Hey, Tomoya, aren't you coming
to the opening ceremony?
Sorry. I'll catch up with you later.
悪い。
ちょっと　先　行っててくれ。
First Press Limited
Amber Concerto
わあ…。
That was careless, Eriri.
≪うかつだったな　英梨々。
うっ！
It's not like you to let a
limited-edition pass you by.
まさか　お前が　初回限定版を
買い逃すなんて。
Well, online retailers did stop
taking orders quite a while ago.
まあ　通販サイトは　だいぶ前に
注文　締め切ってたしな。
Be grateful I placed orders at all the shops selling exclusives as soon as they started taking pre—
予約開始の日に
特典の付く　全部のショップで→
注文した俺に　感謝す…。
Haven't I told you not to speak to me at school?
学校じゃ　話し掛けるなって
言ったわよ。
発売日に　重さ　１．８ｋｇの
ボックスを　５つ　抱えて→
That's what you have to say to the guy who lugged
five 1.8kg boxes around Akiba for you on release day?
秋葉を走り回った俺に対する
ねぎらいの言葉は？
特典タペストリーは
あんたに渡したでしょ。
I let you take the bonus wall scroll, didn't I?
感謝してほしいくらいよ。
You should be thanking me.
だいたい
Ｇ組まで　何しに来たのよ。
Anyway, why did you come over to Class G?
あんた　Ｂ組でしょ？
You're in Class B, aren't you?
You know what class I'm in?
俺のクラス　知ってんのか？
They were only announced today.
今日　発表だったのに。
うっ…。
If that's all you came to say, I'm leaving!
用がないなら　もう　行く！
Hey, wait!
待ってくれ！
大事な話があるんだ。
I have something important to discuss.
もうすぐ　始業式なんだけど。
The opening ceremony is about to start.
今じゃなきゃ　駄目なんだ。
It's now or never.
Please.
頼むよ。
（英梨々）で？
So?
だから　企画書。
For what?
（英梨々）何の？
For the ultimate dating sim
that we're gonna make!
そりゃ　俺たちで作る
最強のギャルゲーのだよ！
And how exactly does someone arrive at such a
nonsensical, stupid, and downright pathetic idea?
何が　どうなったら
そういう意味不明で　バカげた→
痛々しい発想に至るのか
ぜひとも　知りたいわね。
I'm glad you asked!
よくぞ　聞いてくれた。
You see, I had this life-changing event last week!
実はな　先週　すげえイベントが
起こったんだよ！
そのとき　俺　運命っていうか
天啓っていうか→
I felt the hand of something at work that day.
It may have been fate, or a divine revelation!
そういうものを感じたっていうか。
（英梨々）あっ　そう。
なっ　すごいだろ！
Did you now?
It's amazing, isn't it?!
It's just like in a girls' manga
or a romance anime!
まるで　少女漫画か
恋愛アニメか→
Or even a moe light novel
or a dating sim prologue!
萌えラノベか　ギャルゲーの
プロローグみたいだろ？
そうね　何度も見た
使い古されたイベントね。
Yeah, sounds like something well
worn out I've seen a million times.
王道は　面白いから　王道なんだよ。
Well, winning formulas work
because people love them.
だから　俺　あのときの感動を
どうしても表現したくて…。
So I just had to express
what I felt at that moment.
その女の子との出会いを
ゲームにしようって？
You want to base a game on this
chance encounter you had with that girl?
That's right.
This is actually my first time in town...
Mystery Girl
When I saw her, game dialogue, visuals,
and music started flooding through my mind.
あのとき　俺の脳内に→
テキストと　ビジュアルと　音楽が
同時に流れたんだ。
That's how I knew.
それで分かったんだ！
The only way to depict this story is with a game!
この物語を表現するには
ゲームしかないんだって！
そういう話じゃなくて。
That's not what I meant.
どうして　その子を探し出して
告白するって流れにならないの？
How about instead, you find her
and tell her how you feel?
えっ？　何で　３次元の女子に
告白しなきゃならないんだ？
Why would I profess feelings to some 3D girl?
And so now you want to drag me into your
little masturbatory fantasy because... why exactly?
それで？
その　あんたのオナニーに→
あたしを
巻き込もうとする意味は？
Because you're the best illustrator I know of!
そりゃ　俺の知るかぎりじゃ→
お前が
ナンバーワン　イラストレーターだからだよ。
By day, you may be the star of the
Toyogasaki Art Club, Sawamura Spencer Eriri.
豊ヶ崎学園　美術部　エース
澤村・スペンサー・英梨々。
その正体は　隠れオタクにして
超人気　１８禁同人作家。
But by night,
you're a member of "Egoistic Lily",
the super-popular 18+ doujin circle,
Deadlines, deadlines, deadlines, deadlines...
サークル　「ｅｇｏｉｓｔｈｉｃ－ｌｉｌｙ」
（英梨々）《締め切り　締め切り…》
Kashiwagi Eri!
柏木エリ！
だ～か～ら～→
For goodness sake!
How many times have I told you not to utter that name on school grounds?!
学校内で　その名前を出すなって
言ってるでしょ！
やってくれるだろ？
You'll do it, won't you?
You're in, right, Eriri?!
やってくれるよな？　英梨々。
As if, moron!
やるか　バカ！
なっ…。
You promised me back when
we were in elementary school!
お前　小学生のとき
約束したじゃないか！
（倫也）《俺　いつか　必ず
ゲーム会社の社長になる》→
I'm definitely gonna become
president of a game company one day!
And when I do, I'll come and hire you!
《そして
英梨々を迎えに行くから》
（英梨々）《あたし
ずっと待ってる》→
I'll await that day for as long as it takes!
I'm gonna be your company's artist, Tomo-kun!
《絶対　トモ君のゲーム会社の
原画家になる》
（倫也）《英梨々…》
（英梨々）《トモ君…》
Eriri...
Tomo-kun...
（英梨々）わーっ！　小学生が
そんな　具体的過ぎて→
As if elementary school kids would
make a promise that specific and mundane!
夢のない約束なんか　するかー！
We did! I swear we did!
したもん！　絶対　したんだもん！
そこまで　やりたいなら→
If you're that hung up on doing it,
自分で　絵とシナリオ　かいて
作ればいいじゃない！
why don't you just do the
illustrations and scenario yourself?!
Isn't that the doujin way?!
そういうのが　同人活動でしょ？
駄目なんだ。
It wouldn't work.
I couldn't depict that girl's beauty with my skills in a million years.
俺の実力じゃ　決して→
あの女の子の美しさを
表現できない！
そんなに　カワイイ子だったの？
Was she really that cute?
今でも　俺の目に焼き付いている。
The scene is still seared into my eyes.
白いワンピースに　白いベレー。
She wore a white one-piece
dress and a white beret.
風に舞う　桜の花びらに彩られ→
That fleeting glimpse
of her standing atop the hill,
colored by cherry blossoms
dancing in the breeze...
坂の上に立ち尽くす彼女の
はかない姿。
それ　全然　顔のこと
触れてないじゃない。
That doesn't tell me a damn thing
about what she looks like.
あんた　ホントは
覚えてないんじゃないの？
You don't remember what she looks like, do you?
違う！　あんな完璧なイメージ→
Of course I do!
My expressive ability just isn't good
enough to depict that perfect image!
俺の表現力じゃ
追い付かないだけなんだ。
To even attempt to would demean her.
そんなの
彼女を　おとしめることになる。
だからこそ　英梨々の
イラストの力が必要って…。
That's why I need the power of your illustrations!
Anyway, Tomoya...
だいたいね　倫也。
あんた　最初から
考え方が　ゆがんでるのよ。
Your way of thinking is warped in the first place.
I never expected to hear that from a pornographic doujinshi artist.
エロ同人誌　描いてるお前に→
それを言われるとは
思わなかったぞ。
You say this is a project of passion but then you
foist a key element of it off onto someone else.
それだけ　熱く語っておきながら
肝心のところは　人に丸投げとか→
全然　本気が感じられない。
That tells me you aren't serious about this at all.
You're just like a con man claiming to be a producer who just wants to kick back and enjoy the profits.
とにかく
楽して　もうけたいっていう→
プロデューサーとかいう　詐欺師のやり口
そのまんまなのよ。
俺は　そんな
いいかげんな人種とは　違う！
I'm nothing like those half-hearted types!
やる気も情熱も　ある！
I have drive and passion!
And I'm overflowing with ideas!
そして　あふれんばかりの
アイデアだって　ある！
I'm the only man who can bring this project proposal to fruition!
だから　この企画を実現できるのは俺しか…。
Wow, all those ideas you're overflowing with
fit on that scrap of paper, huh?
へ～　あふれんばかりのアイデアがそんな紙切れ一枚に　収まるんだ。
"The protagonist meets a mysterious, beautiful girl.
The two flirt a little and then share a joyous kiss. The end."
「謎の美少女と出会って
イチャイチャして→
２人は　幸せなキスをして終了」
って一行が→
Your idea that only you can bring to fruition fits in a single line.
あんたにしか実現できない
アイデアなんだ。
あー　やめて　やめて　やめて。
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
じゃあね。
Later.
Wait, Eriri!
待ってくれ　英梨々！
Give me one more chance!
Just listen to what I have to say once more!
もう一度！　もう一度だけ
話を聞いてくれ！
もう　話すことなんか　ない。
There's nothing more to say.
今日の放課後
視聴覚室で待ってる。
I'll be waiting in the AV room after school.
いまさら　そんなこと言われたって遅いよ。　倫也。
It's too late to be saying that now, Tomoya.
And now for the presentation of the
top prize for last month's mock exam.
[ﾏｲｸ]（教師）続いて
先月　行われた　全国模試の…。
You seem depressed.
（喜彦）何か　落ち込んでるな。→
Gotten rejected on the first day
of the semester, have you?
新学期早々
女にでもフラれたか？
Not quite.
別に　そういうわけじゃ…。
But I will admit that I am now facing a huge crisis.
だが　大きなピンチが
到来したことだけは　確かだな。
Kasumigaoka Utaha-san of Class 3-C.
[ﾏｲｸ]（教師）３年Ｃ組
霞ヶ丘　詩羽さん。
There now stands between me and my epic project,
worthy of the beginning of my new otaku life—
俺の新たなオタク人生の始まりに
ふさわしい　超特大プロジェクトの前に→
Wow, look, Tomoya!
立ちふさがる…。
あっ　おい。　見ろよ　倫也。
Yoshihiko, you asked me a
question and then ignored me.
だから　喜彦。
人に質問しといて→
Check it out, it's Kasumigaoka-senpai!
それはな…。
ほら　霞ヶ丘先輩だよ。
（喜彦）霞ヶ丘　詩羽。→
Kasumigaoka Utaha, the smartest girl in school.
入学してから　２年間
一度も　学年トップの座を→
She's held her position as top of her class
throughout the two years she's been here.
譲ったことがない
学園一の才女。
相変わらず
マイペースだよなあ。→
Always lost in her own world...
She's always nodding off in class and never does her homework.
授業中も　寝てばっかで→
課題も　全然　やってこないくせに
あれだから→
先生たちも
手に負えないらしいぜ。
But I hear even the teachers can't touch her.
You've never seen any of this for yourself, so stop pretending you know what you're talking about.
実際に見たわけでもないくせに→
何　分かったようなこと
言ってんだよ。
She sure is pretty, though.
（喜彦）にしても
奇麗だよなあ　先輩。→
She's one of the top two beauties
of Toyogasaki Academy.
豊ヶ崎学園　２大美女。→
It's not for nothing that they say Sawamura is the light side to Kasumigaoka's dark side.
表の澤村。　裏の霞ヶ丘って
言われるだけのことはある。
あの２人を並べて語ると→
I wouldn't even be putting those two in the same sentence if I were you.
後で　色々と　問題になるんだぞ。
けどさ　霞ヶ丘先輩も→
But Kasumigaoka-senpai has long, black hair,
黒髪ロング。　巨乳。→
big boobs,
しかも　黒ストッキング。
and black stockings!
Don't you think she's a moe heroine neck and neck with Sawamura-san?
澤村さんに　負けず劣らずの
萌えヒロインだと思わないか？
だからさ　ホント　見た目だけで
語るの　やめようぜ。
I'm telling you, those are two books
you don't want to judge by their covers.
（喜彦）にしても　あの２人って
これだけ騒がれてる割に→
But I have to say,
it's weird that I never see either of them
with guys despite how sought-after they are.
まるで　男の気配がないんだよな。
Do they just hide them away somewhere?
よっぽど　うまく　隠してるのか
それとも　男嫌いなのか。
Or is it perhaps that they hate guys?
Don't ask me.
俺に聞くなよ。
True, talking about it with
Mr. 2D-only isn't going to help me.
（喜彦）まっ　確かに
２次オンリーの倫也に→
そういう話　したってなあ。
There will be class in the afternoon as well!
Don't go home just yet.
Hasumi
Monday, April 6
やっぱ　ここにいた。
I had a feeling I'd find you here.
どうせ　昼飯　まだですよね。
You haven't had lunch yet, have you?
隣　いいですか？
Mind if I join you?
ああ…　はい。
Oh, right.
はい。
Here.
Sho...
"Sho"?
Oo ane doo azg ni zumding, ite?
なには　ようふぁ　ふぁ…。
すいません　全然　分かりません。
Sorry, I can't hear a word you're saying.
So, you came to ask me something, right?
（詩羽）で？
何か用があるんでしょ？→
That's the only reason you would have the gall to show your face
だから　わざわざ
昔　捨てた女の所に→
のこのこ　顔　出したのよね？
to the girl you've long cast aside, isn't it?
Don't say things that will
give people the wrong impression!
そうやって　誤解を生むような
言い方　やめてよ！
どうですか？　俺の企画書。
So what do you think of my project proposal?
俺　こういうの
初めて書くんで→
I've never written one before,
so I'd appreciate any advice you have to offer.
先輩のアドバイス　もらえたら
うれしいなって。
I also have an even bigger favor to ask of you.
で　ここから先は　さらに
厚かましいお願いなんだけど→
I'd be overjoyed if you
came on board the project, so if—
先輩が　この企画に
参加してくれたら→
もっと　うれしいなあって。
（詩羽）ごみは　ごみに。
Rubbish to rubbish. Ashes to ashes. Dust to dust.
I poured my heart and soul into that!
くずは　くずに。
ちりは　ちりに。
ねっ　倫理君。
倫也です。
Listen, Mr. Ethical.
Ethical
Loser
It's Tomoya.
X
Tomoya
This misguided passion of yours,
あなたの間違った方向に
突き抜けた情熱とか→
痛々しいまでに
行き先を見失った青さとか→
this woefully ill-advised naiveté,
and even your wildly misplaced tenacity
aren't without their charms.
勘違いも甚だしい頑張りは
嫌いじゃない。
Aren't those all slightly different
ways of saying the exact same thing?
それ…
色々と　言い方　変えてるだけで→
全部　同じ意味ですよね？
But I can offer no counsel
to something I find undeserving.
でも　評価に値しないものに
助言を与えることはできないわね。
It's that bad?
そんなに　駄目？
As a project proposal I'd give it a score of zero.
取りあえず　企画としては　０点ね。
All I see is a confused mess
of elements I've seen elsewhere.
どこかで見たパーツの
寄せ集めにしか見えないし。
うっ。
ストーリーの　どこを取っても→
You could easily tell where you
found the idea for any part of this story.
簡単に元ネタが割れるし。
あっ。
さらに　悪いことに→
And what's worse, it's so bad that it doesn't even compare to the works you've ripped it from.
全てが　劣化コピーにすら
なっていない　質の低さ。
The more of this I read,
the more I can do nothing but sigh.
もう　読めば読むほど
ため息しか出てこないわね。
そこまで　ひどい？
It's that terrible?
それに　私　今は忙しいし。
Anyway, I'm busy at the moment.
あなたの
思い付きの創作ごっこになんか→
I don't have time to join you with your whimsical "production house" games.
付き合ってられない。
This isn't just a whim!
思い付きなんかじゃない！
ずっと　作りたかったんだ。
I've always wanted to make a game.
俺の　憧れのクリエーターたちに→
I've always wanted to get closer to the
creators I've admired, even if just a little.
ほんの少しでも
近づきたいと思ってたんだよ。
Utaha-senpai, remember what you once told me?
詩羽先輩
前に言ってくれましたよね。
俺には　クリエーターの才能が
あるかもしれないし→
That I may or may not have
what it takes to be a game creator!
ないかもしれないって。
I said that, did I?
そんなこと　言ったかしら。
というか　それって　巧妙な
社交辞令で　ごまかしてない？
You know, that sounds like something
I'd just say in an attempt to be polite.
To me, those words were the one ray of hope
for someone damned to live in this cruel world!
俺にとっては　その言葉が→
たった１本の
クモの糸だったんだよ。
お釈迦様。
The smartest student in the history of
Toyogasaki Academy, Kasumigaoka Utaha,
豊ヶ崎学園　始まって以来の秀才
霞ヶ丘　詩羽。
is in fact...
その正体は
シリーズ　累計５０万部突破。
writer of a series with over 500,000 copies sold, Metronome in Love.
『恋するメトロノーム』　原作者。
超人気　女子高生　ラノベ作家。
Super-popular high-school author,
Kasumi Utako!
霞　詩子！
そのことを知っている
あなただからこそ→
And because you know that, you of all people should understand how busy I am.
私が　本当に忙しいのは
分かっているでしょ？
I heard that you're starting on a new series.
新シリーズ　決まったそうですね。
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
Thank you. Now goodbye.
ありがとう。　それじゃ。
それでも！
But still,
give me one more chance!
もう一度　もう一度だけ→
Please, just listen to what I have to say once more!
話を聞いてください！
今日の放課後
視聴覚室で待ってます！
I'll be waiting in the AV room after school.
どうして　今なのよ。　倫也君。
Why now, Tomoya-kun?
できた。
That's it.
できたぞ！
It's done!
待ってろよ　英梨々。
詩羽先輩！
Just you wait, Eriri, Utaha-senpai!
（恵）あっ　安芸君！
（恵）蓮見先生が
職員室　来てくれって。→
Hasumi-sensei wants you
to go to the faculty room.
何か　視聴覚室に
教材　運んでほしいみたい。
It sounds like she wants you to take
some class materials to the AV room.
Sorry, but at the present moment, I cannot.
悪いけど　今は　行けない。
俺には　今　どうしても→
I have something else that I
absolutely must do immediately.
やらなくちゃならないことが
あるんだ。
Oh, okay.
（恵）そっか。
じゃあ　私が先生に断っておくね。
I'll go tell her you said no, then.
悪いな。　あした　早く来て
やっとくって　伝えといてくれ。
Sorry. You can tell her I'll
come in early tomorrow to do it.
（恵）分かった　伝えとく。
じゃあな！
All right, I will.
Later.
（恵）あっ　それとさ…。
今度は何だ？
Oh, and by the way.
What is it now?
Thanks for earlier.
（恵）この前　ありがとね。
何のことだ？
For what?
You picked my hat up for me
over spring break, remember?
ほら　春休みのとき
帽子　拾ってくれたじゃん。
白いベレーの。
The white beret.
Did I, now?
そんなこと　あったっけ？
覚えてないな。
I don't remember.
I suppose that's unsurprising.
It was several days ago.
まあ　そうだよね。
何日も　前のことだもんね。
それじゃ。
ああ　また　あしたな。
See you.
Yeah, see you tomorrow.
AV Room
別に　引き受けるつもりなんか
ないからね。
Just because I came, doesn't mean
I plan to get on board, got it?
ただ　ずっと　待ってられても
寝覚めが悪いから→
I only came to hear you out so I could still sleep without thinking I'd left you out here all night.
話だけは
聞いてあげようかなって。
That's a laudable sentiment, Sawamura-san.
（詩羽）それは　殊勝な心掛けね。
（英梨々）はっ！
（詩羽）澤村さん。
But I'm afraid I don't have anything prepared for you to hear out.
まあ　私の方から　話すことなんて
ないけど。
Kasumigaoka Utaha?!
霞ヶ丘　詩羽。
いいかげん　人のことを
わざわざ　フルネームで呼ぶの→
Would you mind not calling me by my full name,
やめてくれないかしら。
澤村・スペンサー・英梨々さん。
Sawamura Spencer Eriri-san?
何で　あんたが　ここに！？
What are you doing here?
偶然ね　澤村さん。
What a coincidence, Sawamura-san.
私も　今　まさに　それを
聞こうと思っていたところよ。
I was just about to ask you
that very same question.
まさか
あんたも　倫也に誘われて？
Wait, you weren't asked to come here by Tomoya, were you?
ゲームって言うから
妙な予感は　していたけれど→
I did have a nagging suspicion
when he said he wanted to make a game,
まさか　キャラクターデザインに
あなたを指名するとはね。
but I can't believe he had you
in mind for character designs.
What's that fool thinking, asking a
gloomy girl like you to do scenario writing?
こんな　根暗女に
シナリオ　頼むなんて→
何　考えてんのよ！　あのバカ！
それを言うなら→
If you're going to play that card,
外づらは完璧だけど
中身が　超ろくでなしの→
is it really wise to entrust illustrations
to a delinquent sham of a proper young lady
偽装お嬢さまに　イラストを
頼むのは　いいのかしら？
who puts up a perfect appearance despite being rotten to the core?
誰が　ろくでなしよ！
Who are you calling a delinquent?!
私　確かに根暗だけど→
True, I may be a gloomy person,
but at least I am true to myself, unlike you.
あなたよりは
素直な性格してるつもりよ。
だいたい　あんなバカに
ちょっと頼られたからって→
Anyway, I hope you're not getting on board
just because that idiot asked you to, you loner!
ほいほい　釣られてるんじゃ
ないわよ。　このボッチ。
You're not one to talk, seeing as how you're doing exactly the same thing.
（詩羽）今　ここで　私と
まったく同じ行動を取っている→
あなたに　言われたくないわね。
I only came here to stop him!
あたしは
あいつを止めに来ただけよ！
あんな　無茶な企画　絶対
うまくいくわけ　ないんだから！
That crazy project has
no hope at all of working out!
Couldn't you have stopped him by simply
not showing up and letting the project fall apart?
あなたが　ここに来なければ
その　無茶な企画とやらも→
自然消滅するんじゃないかしら。
（英梨々）あたし　帰る。
I'm out of here.
Okay. Goodbye.
（詩羽）そう　さようなら。
まさか　あんたは残るっての？
Don't tell me you're going to stay?
あんな　バカバカしい　ほら話を
真に受けて。
Are you really buying into that absurd story of his?
I don't see how that is any of your concern.
そんなの　別に
あなたに話すことじゃないし。
（英梨々）くっ…。
ちょっと　待て～！
Wait a minute!
ハァー　ハァー。
（恵）ん？　何？
What is it?
You're...
お前が…　お前が…。
You're the...
私が　何？
I'm the what?
あのときの　帽子の…。
That hat was—
Looks like we're in the same class again.
ことしも　同じクラスだね。
よろしく　安芸君。
Let's have a good year together, Aki-kun.
《ある春の日
俺は　運命と出合った》
One spring day...
I came face to face with my destiny.
えっと…　加納　恵だっけ？
Um, Kanou Megumi, right?
加藤だよ。
It's "Katou".
あっ　だよな～　だと思ったわ。
《けど　それは　どうやら→
Oh, right! Yeah, I knew that.
But now it seems to have been a misunderstanding.
まごうことなき
勘違いだったらしい》
bye-bye no ato samenai binetsu
After every good-bye, my cheeks are always warm
w
yokaze ni fukare kangaeru
And as I feel the wind against them, I always think
suki kirai kirai suki kurikaesu
Love? Hate? Hate? Love? Over and over
sono hitomi ni utsutteiru no wa
What are you seeing in those eyes of yours?
real sore tomo nijigen
Reality or something 2-D?
tayasuku kawaii da nante iwanai de yo ne
Don't just say I look pretty like it's no big deal to me
ashita mo me wo kosutte ohayou wo itte
Tomorrow, you'll rub your eyes and say "good morning"
tawai mo nai koto takusan oshiete
And talk about all sorts of pointless stuff
sukoshizutsu chikadzuiteku kyori ni
And as we slowly grow closer together
doushiyou jibun ja nai mitai da
What do I do? What am I usually like?
merry-go-round ga tomaranakute
This merry-go-round just never stops
mawaru mawaru keshiki ga kawatteku
Spinning, spinning, the scenery blurs by
colorful na yume wo miru
Like a colorful dream
dokudoku shite karadajuu wo
Throb, throb, I can feel them inside
meguru meguru kimochi
Going 'round and 'round, these feelings
mada kotoba ni dekinakute
I still can't put them into words
hitokoto sore de juubun nanoni
Even though one word would be enough
（詩羽）来ないわね。
We've been stood up.
Yeah.
（英梨々）うん…。